Guide to the Division of Finance & Administration RG 4
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Division of Finance & Administration,
1906-2007
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Western Connecticut State University. Division of Finance & Administration
RG 4
112
2 Linear Feet 3 boxes
The records of the Office of Finance and Administration contain records from the following departments under the V.P. for Finance & Administration: Fiscal Affairs, Institutional Services, and the Division of Public Safety. Also incuded are University Events' invitations and programs from commencements, convocations and events from 1906-2007.
Provenance
Transferred to the Archives in 2004.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The V.P. for Finance & Adminstration currently oversees the following departments: Administrative Services, University Police, Financial Planning & Budgeting, Fiscal Affairs and the Associate V.P. for Facilities.
The University Events department now report to University Relations and University Computing now reports directly to the President.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Office of Finance and Administration are divided into 5 series: (1) Fiscal Affairs, (2) Institutional Services, (3) Division of Public Safety, (4) University Computing, and (5) University Events.
Included with in this collection when accessioned were records which were assigned to series groupings of University Computing, and University Events. These are no longer departments in the Finance and Administration department nor are they currently actual series in the Finance and Administration record group.
The bulk of the collection is located in Series 5, University Events, which contain honors and commencement programs and invitations. Additional invitations and programs for faculty recognition luncheons, banquets, retirement luncheons, and other social events can also be found in this series. Folder 85 contains memorial service programs for James Furman, professor of music and director of the Concert Choir at WCSU for more than 25 yrs, and Anthony V. Ficarra who taught modern languages. Also included is the dedication service program for Curley Hall, named in honor of Thomas F. Curley, a student who died suddenly while attending DTC in 1949.
In 1920 a small booklet entitled Commencement Season of Normal School listed events for seniors to attend prior to graduation. From 1939 to 1951 the booklet was called Commencement Week and contained a series of activities such as dancing, picnic, class day and dinner, games, and amateur skits.
Folders 27 and 77 contain the text of commencement speeches given by Dr. William J. Sanders, Commissioner of Education (1969); Dr. Ralph Braibanti and James B. Duke, Professor of Political Science Emeritus, Duke University (1995).
The 40th Annual Student Honors Convocation took place in 1999. Prior to this time, the Honors Convocation programs contained names of students who were honored by the School of Arts & Sciences, Professional School, Ancell School of Business, and the University Awards. In 2000 each school began to publish separate programs, and in 2001 a fourth program for University Awards was published.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged alphabetically in each series.
The files are grouped into 5 series:
Missing Title
Fiscal Affairs
Institutional Services
Public Safety, Division of
University Computing
University Events (Invitations & Programs)
Related Material
Office of Institutional Advancement Records
Reports.; Pamphlets.; Danbury (Conn.); Souvenir programs.; Correspondence.; Universities and colleges -- Administration.; Invitations.; Danbury Normal School.; Danbury State College.; Western Connecticut State University. Division of Finance & Administration; Western Connecticut State College.; Furman, James, 1937-1989; Danbury Teachers College.; Scollin, Anna E.; Ficarra, Anthony V.; Feldman, Stephen.
- Series 1. Fiscal Affairs, 38197
  - Expenditure Plan (Narrative Exhibits, and Capital Projects), 1992-1993; 38203 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Navigating in Banner, 2000; 38202 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Spending Plan FY '97, 1996; 38201 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Spending Plan FY '98, 1997; 38200 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Spending Plan FY '99, 1998; 38199 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Spending Plan FY 1999-2000, 38198 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series 2. Institutional Services, 38195
  - Catering booklets and correspondence, 1985-1998; 38196 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Series 3. Public Safety, Division of, 38185
  - Campus Safety Reports, 1988-1998; 38194 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Campus Safety Reports, 1990; 52864 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Campus Safety Reports, 2000; 38193 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Campus Safety Reports, 2001; 38192 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Campus Safety Reports, 2002; 38191 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Campus Safety Reports, 2003; 38190 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Campus Safety Reports, 2004; 38189 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Campus Safety Reports, 2005; 38188 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Campus Security Report, 2006; 52862 (Box 3, Folder 11.1)
    General
    WCSU Campus Libraries Security Survey also contained in folder
  - Campus Security Report, 2008; 52863 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Miscellaneous, undated; 38187 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Pamphlets, etc., 1998-2007; 38186 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Safe-T-Net, 1998-1999; 52865 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - WCSU Police Crime Reports, 1992-2002; 52866 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Series 4. University Computing, 38179
  - Keegan, Robert H.; David E. Bell, and David S. Evans. Information Technology Terms and Concepts. Draft Date Jan 31, 1995., 38184 (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  - School of Arts & Sciences Technology Plan, 1997; 38183 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - WCSU Information Systems/Computer Center, Version 1.1, 1988; 38182 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - WCSU Information Systems/Computer Center 1993, 38181 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - WCSU Information Technology Study 1994, 38180 (Box 3, Folder 6-7)
  - WCSU Information Systems/Computer Center, Version 1.2, Aug. 1, 1989; 52809 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Guide to RESNET, 2006-2007; 52810 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Series 5. University Events (Invitations & Programs), 38081
  - Danbury Normal School Field Day (program), 1921, 1925; 38122 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Danbury State Teachers College Opening (program), 1937; 38121 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - EA&P, Educational Achievement and Access Program, 2001; 38120 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Emeritus Faculty Luncheon (invitation), 1994-1995; 38119 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty Recognition Ceremony (programs), 1992-2008; 38118 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
  - Feldman, Stephen Farewell Luncheon (invitation & program), 1992; 38117 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Forum, The Annual Banquet (program), 1938-1940; 38116 (Box 2, Folder 8-9)
  - Invitations (misc.), 1972; 38089 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Junior Exercises, 1936; 38088 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Leopold Dr. John A. "A Testimonial", 2003; 38087 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Memoriam Services, 1988-1989; 38086 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Retirement/Recognition Events, 1972-2003; 38085 (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
  - Scollin, Anna E., 1941; 38084 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - WCSU, Fifth Anniversary of University Status Celebration, 1988; 38083 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous Certificates, 1961-1964; 38082 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Planning and Engineering, 52882
  - Five Year Facilities Plan for 1995-2000 (Biennum FYFP 95-97), 1994; 52883 (Box 3, Folder 16)